<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolio on Clark Kromenaker</title><link>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolio on Clark Kromenaker</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</managingEditor><webMaster>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skullgirls 2nd Encore</title><link>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/skullgirls-2e/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</author><guid>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/skullgirls-2e/</guid><description/></item><item><title>G-Engine</title><link>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/gengine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</author><guid>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/gengine/</guid><description>G-Engine is a game engine passion project that I started developing in 2017. It is intended to be a complete C++ rewrite of the game engine for Gabriel Knight 3: Blood of the Sacred, Blood of the Damned, a 3D adventure game released in 1998 by Sierra Studios.
GK3 is a mostly data-driven game; even most of the gameplay logic is implemented using a custom scripting language. As a result, you can write an engine that is able to parse and utilize these data files to recreate the original experience (or improve upon it).</description></item><item><title>Skullgirls Mobile</title><link>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/skullgirls/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</author><guid>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/skullgirls/</guid><description>Skullgirls Mobile is a whole new handheld fighting game experience in the universe of the hit PC and console game! It is a true fighting game experience on your mobile device - one that&amp;rsquo;s easy to pick up for casual players, but still challenging for fighting game experts.
Skullgirls&amp;rsquo; unique art style hearkens back to classic 2D fighting games, while boasting high-fidelity and lush graphics for modern-day hardware. The mobile game&amp;rsquo;s graphics pack the same punch as the original - spare no expense!</description></item><item><title>Threes</title><link>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/threes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</author><guid>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/threes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Tic Tactics</title><link>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/tictactics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</author><guid>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/tictactics/</guid><description>Tic Tactics was a turn-based competitive online game where you played the classic game Tic-Tac-Toe&amp;hellip;but with a twist!
In Tic Tactics, you play nine games of tic-tac-toe, laid out in a 3x3 grid. You must win three &amp;ldquo;sub-boards&amp;rdquo; across to win the game! It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;tic-tac-toe-ception!&amp;rdquo;
Additionally, each move you make dictates which sub-board your opponent can play on in their next turn. So there&amp;rsquo;s another layer of strategy to not only win the current sub-board, but avoid sending your opponent to a sub-board that would help them win.</description></item><item><title>Bag It!</title><link>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/bagit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>kromenak@gmail.com (Clark Kromenaker)</author><guid>https://clarkkromenaker.com/portfolio/bagit/</guid><description>Bag It! is a light and fun mobile game that puts your grocery bagging skills to the test!
It may seem easy to bag your groceries, but there&amp;rsquo;s more to it than meets the eye. Avoid crushing fragile items, group related groceries for bonus points, complete challenges, and manage the personalities of an array of temperamental groceries. Become the ultimate grocery bagger through six modes of play and 100+ levels!</description></item></channel></rss>